



# Nur Hakim Soleh

Jakarta, Indonesial +6281809669575 | Noorhakim.s91@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/nur-hakim-soleh-7615b9b5 | l https://github.com/omeganoor

### SUMMARY

Software Engineer with 6+ years of experience and passion in distributed systems. Familiar with maintaining and improving the reliability, availability, and scalability of complex microservice systems at both the application level (circuit breakers, feature toggles, multithreading) and architecture level (zero-downtime deployments, load-balancing, distributed tracing).

# WORK EXPERIENCE

### Senior Software Engineer

January 2022 - Present

Produgie Pte Ltd — Saas Company that Empower Business Growth and Innovation.

### Responsibilities

- Create and designing technical flow and developing produgie system.
- · Rewrite and redesigning legacy code from scala to java springboot.
- Tech stacks: Java, Spring boot 2, MySql, GIT, RESTful, postman, Jira, Docker, GCP and Linux servers.

### Achievement 1

- Adding and integrating user tagging system on admin console.
- Adding .Team Module feature for manager/team leader to create plan to growth their team member.
- Rewrite and redesigning action plan library items.

### Local Technical Support Engineer

May 2021 - January 2022

Element Inc — AI Company that focusing on biometrics authentication.

### Responsibilities

- · Implement and support local client in Indonesia
- Tech stacks: Java, MySQL, GIT, RESTful, postman, GitHub, Jira, Docker, GCP and Linux servers.

### Achievement 1

- Implementing liveness detection on myIndihome application.
- Implementing biometrics authentication and e-kyc solution for Amartha.com.

### Senior Software Engineer

September 2020 - May 2021

2K Games - contractor (AccelByte Inc) — Game Developer Company that develop supporting tools for game developer.
Responsibilities

- Maintaining Login and Membership system at 2K.
- Create and designing technical flow and developing new Login and Membership feature for 2K Games Backend System.
- · Rewrite 2k portal account.
- Tech stacks: Java, Golang, Spring boot 2, NoSQL(mongo DB), GIT, RESTful, postman, GitHub, Jira Docker, AWS
  cluster and Linux servers.

### Achievement 1

- · Adding and integrating with Zendesk API to allow user to login using Zendesk account.
- · Create new scheduler service to send email verification and update age group for 2k account.
- Rewrite 2k portal account (<a href="https://accounts.2k.com/en-US">https://portal.2k.com/</a>) from monolith (Django) to microservices using Golang.

### **Technical Architect Delivery Specialist**

June 2020 - September 2020

Accenture — Leading IT Consulting solution in the world that helps all business segments to digitize their business. Responsibilities

- Maintained a system of microservices consisting of 20+ service clusters with more than 1000tps.
- Creating Technical design and technical flow to rewriting ESB application to microservices application.
- Developing, testing and conducting code review for middle and junior programmers.
- Tech stacks: Java, Spring boot 2, Spring JPA, Hibernate, oracle, GIT, Postman, Gitlab, and Linux server.

# Achievement 1

- Improved ESB performance by rewrite and redesigning the system.
- Rewrite ESB monolithic application to java microservices application.





### Senior Software Engineer

March 2019 - May 2020

Tiket.com — Leading Southeast Asia online travel company that provides a wide range of travel needs in one platform. Responsibilities

- Maintained a system of microservices consisting of 30+ service clusters for payment and promotion system at tiket.com.
- · Creating Technical design and technical flow for new payment feature at tiket.com.
- Leading a small team for the rewrite project consists of the frontend, backend, and QA team from dev to deployment, in 3 months.
- Maintained separate server environments for dev, testing and production.
- Tech stacks: Java, Reactive Java, Golang, Spring boot 2, Spring Web flux, Rx Java, Spring JPA, SQL(PostgreSQL),
   NoSQL(mongo DB), GIT, Docker, RESTful, Kafka, postman, GitHub, Jira and Linux servers.

#### Achievement 1

- Adding and integrating some new wallet (GOPAY, LINKAJA) and in store payment (Lawson Group) system to
  payment system at tiket.com
- Migrating and Redesigning Promo code and Gift Voucher from monolith application to microservices application using reactive java (Rx java & spring web flux).
- · Creating an open API to generate Gift Voucher for the customer.
- Creating a Gift Card Product to sell our Gift Voucher directly to our customer.
- Creating a Promo Suggestion system to suggest the available promo to our customer when they checkout their purchase.

### Software Engineer

January 2018 - February 2019

ATI Business Group — Software House Company that creates custom applications for airlines and travel industries . Responsibilities

- Launched the product by building the frontend, backend APIs, databases, from dev to deployment, in 6 months.
- Maintained separate server environments for dev, testing and production.
- Tech stacks: Java, SQL(MySQL), NoSQL(mongoDB), Angular, GIT, Docker, Spring Boot, Spring JPA, XML, RESTful, eclipse, bitbucket, Jira and Linux servers.

### Achievement 1

- Developing FALCON it is a HRIS management system for managing employee absence, leave, and payroll in ATI Business Group.
- Developing Fare Management System for Garuda Indonesia airlines. It is a webs application to create, manage and
  distribute their fares to GDS(global distributed system for ticketing airlines) and also to compare their prices with their
  competitors to determine their competitive fares.

### Software Engineer

April 2016 - January 2018

Bank Tabungan Pensiunan Nasional (BTPN) — Top 10 Private Bank in Indonesia.

Responsibilities

- Launched the product by building backend APIs, databases, from dev to deployment, in 6 months.
- Research, Design, Developing and Testing Back End Switching Application (Banking Switching Application) for financial transactions at BTPN.
- · Maintained ATM Channel at BTPN.
- Tech stacks: Java, Oracle PL/SQL, ISO8583, FINSim, NDC Protocol, SOAP XML, IBM CIT, SVN, Tranzware Software Application and Linux (RHEL), OpenShift.

### Achievement 1

- Developing ATM Decline Fee Feature. This is a project to apply fees if there are btpn customer transactions that fail on all ATM networks in Indonesia.
- Developing Visa Business Enhancement Requirement (VISA BER). Developing enhancement in our system to comply
  with visa system updates.
- Developing Jenius Onboarding System. It's a project for making a service for onboarding process for new customers in BTPN jenius product.
- National Payment Gateway (NPG). It's a project to make a gateway for 3rd party networks like ATM Bersama and prima for enabling all purchase transactions from all other Bank EDC devices.

# Junior Software Engineer

October 2015 - March 2016

**Oberthur Tech** — Software House Company that creates smart chips applications for telco and ATM cards. Responsibilities





- · Developing simple smart card applications using java applet.
- Tech stacks: Java, PCOM, Python, QT C++ and GIT.

### Achievement 1

- · Creating sim toolkits applications for telco providers using java card technology.
- · Creating roaming broker application for telco sim card.

### Implementation Engineer

October 2014- September 2015

Xlink Software — Software House Company that creates switching applications for Banking industries .

Responsibilities

- Configuring, testing, implementing and documenting Banking Financial Transaction system according to the client needed for Banking Company.
- Tech stacks: Java (JPOS), Xlink Software, Sybase SQL, NDC Protocol, Linux (SUSE)

#### Achievement 1

- Configuring and implementing ATM menu enhancement for Bank DKI, Bank riau, and Bank Bukopin.
- Configuring and implementing NSICCS project for Bank Riau and BAnk Kalbar NSICCS Project is a project which is
  required by the government for all banks in Indonesia where the bank must replace all its ATM cards from magnetic
  stripe cards to chip cards.

### Avionic Engineer (Intern)

December 2012 - February 2013

Garuda Indonesia maintenance Facility — Airlines Maintenance Facility owned by Garuda Indonesia Airlines. Responsibilities

- Designing & modified tools for downloading and uploading data from and to the airplane system.
- Tech stacks: PCB Software (Protel 2004, and Proteus 7.10), Microcontroller Software/C programming, Arduino.

#### Achievement 1

Designing & modified tools for downloading and uploading data from and to the airplane system.

### EDUCATION

| Institute Technology Bandung | 2009-2014 |
|------------------------------|-----------|
| Bachelor's Degree in Physics | 2009-2014 |

- Relevant courses: Basic Programming, Electrical and Instrumentation Systems, Computational Physics.
- As a Lab assistant: Elementary Physics, Computational Physics, Electronic Physics, Advance Physics.

### Master's Degree Candidate in Computer Science

2021-2022

 Relevant courses: Basic Programming, Basic Algorithm, Computer Architecture, Data Management System, Machine Learning, Pattern Recognition.

### SKILLS

- 6+ years of Developing and maintaining a highly scalable, highly available Backend services application.
- Deep understanding of distributed systems architectures, components, fallacies, and potential issues.
- Fluent in Java and Spring Boot (Spring Web flux, Rx Java, Reactive Java).
- Familiar with C, C++, Go, Python, JavaScript (Node.js), HTML, CSS.
- Experienced in Git, Linux, Docker, Kafka, RabbitMQ, Oracle, MySQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL.
- Experience in Git, SVN, Jira, GitHub, Gitlab, Bitbucket, Perforce, Jenkins, Eclipse, and IntelliJ.
- Proficient in writing Linux scripts using Bash and other available tools.
- Working knowledge of core CS and SWE concepts: data structures, algorithms, OS, networking, concurrency.
- Worked using distributed systems monitoring tools such as Grafana, Kibana, Scalyr, and New Relic.
- Familiar with cloud technologies and services GCP and leveraging managed solutions to solve problems.
- Familiar with ISO8583, NDC Protocol and other banking protocols.